hi and welcome back to Polar Ice creamy
I'm Nick and today we are going to make
mango ice cream using canned mangoes a
lot of people have asked for this
because you know they're not in season
all the time and the season is quite
short apparently so let's take our mord
mangoes and make some of the best mango
ice cream you're ever going to
eat so yeah a lot of people ask about
mango ice cream
um it's not something I eat that often
to be fair it's not a flavor that I pick
out and choose but let's just briefly
talk about mango ice cream just for a
minute um
mangoes can be traced back you know
4,000
years um they were they're
originally or people believe that they
originally cultivated in Southeast Asia
which kind of makes sense the growing
climate and conditions needed for
mangoes mango ice cream is also believed
to have originated in India uh in in
India the mango is the king of fruits
that is what it's known as it has a very
specific window of growth and they're
not in season all the time and people
love mango ice cream so one thing that
is common out of season you can get
canned
mangoes now I've had a look around the
supermarkets local to me and this is
what I've got I think I can go to the
other side of Calgary and get some so
we're going to try it with these first
see how we get on so I've used the ice
cream calculator and come up with this
recipe I've tried it it's beautiful so
if you want to know what it takes to
make amazing mango ice cream from a
cheap ass can of
mangoes let's do it so the first thing
we're going to do is get our pan and
warming up and we're going to do this in
two stages stage one in here we have our
milk and our cream and in here we have
our sucros our dextrose and our skim
milk powder so you don't need to stir
this
up what we're going to do is just pour
all of this in
there and then get our
whisk so we're just going to warm this
gently doesn't need to be any more than
you know 4 50° we just want to make sure
that those sugars and that skin milk
powder are completely dissolved into the
dairy once your sugar's completely
dissolved we're going to turn off the
heat and take it over here because over
here is our nice shiny new blender this
is exactly the same one that I had back
in the
UK and we
are we're going to pour
our Dairy and sugar mix into there and
then also into
there we are going to take our mangoes
and this is the entire cans worth of
mangoes the cam is
398 ML and we
got exactly the right amount of mango
flesh out of there which is
amazing so we're going to just gently
drop those in
might as well add that in as well free
water nothing's free in this in this
world here we
go we're going to pop our lid on down
we're going to blend this for just 5 to
10 seconds to get it
started okay now that we're at that
stage we're going to just pop the lid
off and here we have our stabilizer in
here we've got 4 G of dextrose and our
zanam
gum that is going in like so put the lid
back
on and blend it for 2
minutes there we go 2 minutes in the
blender that zanam gum is
completely incorporated into that Dairy
nice texture we're going to put that in
a bowl and put it in the
fridge
machine's been chilling down for 10 15
minutes straight out of the fridge what
we're going to do is strain this into a
clean Bowl just to make sure that
there's no big lumps
of of fruit in
there
nice no that came through super
smooth
let's get this in the
machine and then when it's ready we'll
get some scooped out and see how this
turned
[Music]
out mango ice cream American style mango
ice cream
so loads of
dairy subtle yellow color let's Dish It
Up
first thing to know is it scooped
nicely smells like mango color is not
overly
strong what does it taste
like texture is lovely smooth creamy
base that's what I wanted to
achieve color I don't mind a color I'm
not going to add artificial color to
this to make it look bright orange
because that defeats the point of making
all these ice creams flavor it's subtle
you can definitely taste the mango there
you know what it is and you can tell
that when you're eating it that is mango
ice cream I'm not sure the flavor is
strong
enough I
think I'm going
to I think I'm going to try this one
again I'm going to do mango ice cream
take two this is a delicious mango ice
cream it it's
refreshing it's
creamy yeah it's really really nice
refreshing fruit ice cream but I wanted
more of that punch color which I just
didn't get so what I'm going to do is
I'm going to adjust the recipe even more
cuz this is kind of a gelato
technically I'm going to adjust the
recipe and use a lot more mango and
bring the fat percentage down so that we
can try and get a color boost and a
Flavor Boost as well so I'd also like to
thank my supporters of the channel
they're coming from
Kofi patreon and on YouTube itself so a
really huge thank you to everyone that
has supported me over the time I should
put a list on the screen so you can see
you know just to say thank you to you
really it really really means a lot that
you are willing to to help me on this
ice cream journey and it's great to have
you here it this ice cream Journey has
been going on for a few years now this
year
we've I think the time of filming this
we're at
4,130 subscribers so thanks very much
for watching don't forget to like And
subscribe and come back when we do mango
gelato take two
[Music]